PETER HOLGATE

CSO & AGENCY LEADER

07730 592 903 | peterjholgate@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a creative and empathetic senior leader with board-level experience. I have a strong track record in helping agencies and clients with brand and business transformation and creating positive momentum in real world results. I love to make things, get involved and get things done. It's the complex opportunities that are difficult to unlock that excite me the most as I like to simplify things and create real, positive action for customers, clients, employees and shareholders.

CORE STRENGTHS

- Business & marketing leadership
- Omnichannel digital & data marketing transformation
- Hands-on and empathetic approach that creates results and high-performing teams
- Storytelling & strategic marketing processes
- Client management & relationship building

EXPERTISE

- Brand strategy & activation
- Digital content and data-driven marketing ecosystems
- Demand generation & ABM
- CRM and loyalty programmes
- B2C and B2B
- FMCG, technology, financial services, auto, consumer health and retail

EXPERIENCE

CHIEF STRATEGY OFFICER

MRM UK | SEPTEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2024

Clients: Sanofi, Cigna Healthcare, LEGO, Nespresso and Santander

Under a new CEO I refocused and re-structured the agency around a return to a CRM core specialism to create growth.

- Identified the opportunities for growth and created agency wide strategy and forward plans that enabled a tangible change in focus, attitude and revenue growth of 10% in the last 12 months.
- Reshaped the agency story internally and externally around modern CRM to rebuild our reputation enabling an increase in new business conversion rates to 84% (from a low of 25%) and making £1.3m net revenue from organic growth in 2023.
- Restructured and energised the planning team for modern CRM skills and a creative mindset.
- Leader on the Al Council in McCann Worldgroup to integrate Al into strategy and creative ways of working to increase productivity, effectiveness, efficiency and creativity.
- On the McCann Worldgroup Integration Board fostering greater collaboration and working practices between nine UK agencies. Implementing a new agency product around CRM's role in dynamic content engines to increase revenue and margin from inter-agency and clients growing inter network revenue from 5% to 41% of agency revenue in 18 months.

Awards: Campaign Agency of the year - Bronze Award 2023 ANA B2 Gold Award - Large Agency of the year

HEAD OF STRATEGIC PLANNING

MRM UK | FEBRUARY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2022

Clients: Sanofi, Nurofen, Microsoft, John Lewis Finance, Mitsubishi Electric and Honeywell

Built and led a high performing planning team to create a more digitally driven and advertising focused department and raise creative output across brand building and digital experiences and data driven marketing ecosystem content disciplines.

- Took our flagship client Allegra to the number one allergy brand worldwide with a new digital centric global strategic and creative platform that created a 38% uplift in conversion, a 44% increase in purchase intent and a 12.5% increase in revenue in key markets.
- Created a cohesive and collaborative sense of team within the planning department and in the working relationship with the creative department to increase the quality and efficiency of creating great creative output.
- Led on-boarding and marketing strategy definition with new clients.
- Introduced new agency ways of working, building upon the success of the Sanofi delivery and helping to replicate the success in this new discipline for MRM London.
- Designed and implemented a streamlined agency brief and briefing processes, along with templates, enhancing agency efficiency and elevating the creative product.
- Built an incremental pipeline of strategic revenue of £400k+ per year through providing customer journey mapping services to other McCann World Group agencies.

Awards: Campaign Agency Of The Year 2021 - Customer Engagement

LEAD PLANNING DIRECTOR

MRM UK | JUNE 2017 - FEBRUARY 2018

Clients: Three Mobile, Halfords, BP, Microsoft, Vauxhall, Subway and Cisco

Under new leadership brought in to integrated MRM Meteorite into the McCann Worldgroup family of agencies following the merger in late 2016, I was promoted to Lead Planning Director to build the Planning Team's ability in multichannel customer contact programmes and data driven marketing activity across all agency clients - B2B and B2C.

- Migrated 1.7million TSB customers to a new banking platform and protected their NPS of 35 in spite the famous systems failures.
- Business-cased, planned and launched the Halfords Club new Driving Loyalty Programme.
- Launched a new Loyalty Programme BP Me to help them take control of their loyalty relationship in a move away from Nectar.
- Launched the UK's fastest 5G network to customers and prospects for Three Mobile street-bystreet to help meet sell-out targets in year one.
- Reignited Vauxhall's Ready-to-buy programme with digital experiences and content to create an increase in marketing leads for dealerships.

Awards: DMA Grand Prix 2018 & Cannes Lion Grand Prix eCommerce for Microsoft 'Fanchise'

SENIOR STRATEGIC PLANNER

MRM METEORITE | JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2017

Clients: TSB, DLG, Nespresso, MoneyCorp and Cisco

Created business and marketing strategies that created a meaningful and profitable relationship between businesses, brands and customers. I worked across their customer journeys from consideration and conversion to loyalty and CRM.

- Helped TSB launch as a new standalone brand and deliver on its customer promises building NPS to an industry-leading score of 35.
- Helped DLG increase retention rates to 20% and sales rates to 5% by creating customer experiences around their lives, not just communications.
- Helped Cisco build connect with Small Businesses across EMEA with it's new Wi-Fi technology

Awards: DLG Red Saturday DMA Award - Gold for Best Financial Service & Bronze Best Use of Email

SENIOR STRATEGIC PLANNER

HEYHUMAN & CLOSER | MARCH 2013 - JUNE 2015

Clients: Lloyds TSB, HBOS, McCoys, William Hill, Guinness, and Glyndebourne

I made the move across to planning as the Lead Brand and Activation Strategist for the clients at HeyHuman and Closer. I was also a core member of the team that repositioned the agency HeyHuman around behavioural economics theory and in refining Closer's proposition around restricted marketing specialism.

SENIOR ACCOUNT MANAGER

BILLINGTON CARTMELL | APRIL 2006 - MARCH 2013

Clients: Lloyds TSB, Morrisons, Ribena, Lucozade and Horlicks

Made the move into agency by joining Billington Cartmell to work on their new client Lloyds TSB and help them take retail banking into the modern branch era. I also used my skills and experience from Foxtons to created impact and sales for brands in owned and retail channels with Promotional, Retail and Shopper marketing brand activation.

MARKETING & PR MANAGER

FOXTONS | MAY 2003 - APRIL 2006

My first job in marketing as part of a small, entrepreneurial team with direct and regular contact with the founder John Hunt. Here I learned how to disrupt traditional sector with innovative marketing through the Minis, the website and the café-style offices that disrupted the market and have become the category standard for estate agencies.

EDUCATION

BSc in Business and Management - 2:1 University of Bradford